A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, History of the University, Confidential papers FA913
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Endowments (property), mainly copies (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - copy of letter JDR to RIMR Trustees giving an additional $350,000 for cost overruns on new building 1906-1910 copies of correspondence JDR to RIMR regarding land and buildings, 1915 April 17
  - NYC Public Works to RIMR permission to pave 67th Street and copy of Resolution adopted by Commissioners of the Sinking Fund, 1916 May 31
  - Indenture with NYC 67th Street and 64th Street for $171,100 less $34,200, 1927-1928?
- Endowments for Hospital (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - copies of correspondence JDR; L. Emmett Holt; Simon Flexner; Board RIMR regarding land plans and building of the Hospital, 1907-1910
  - Copies of news releases on opening of the Hospital
- Gates, F.T. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Essay prepared for the General Education Board "The Colleges and Rural Life"
- Institute site (temporary) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Copy of lease with Nursery and Child's Hospital for buildings at 50th and Lexington, 1904 June 23
- Meningitis outbreak in Dallas (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Sophien loaned from NYC Health Department to use RIMR serum in treatment, 1912
  - Copies of correspondence between W.H. Park and Simon Flexner regarding newspaper report
- Microorganisms, 1917 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Hermann M. Biggs to Henry James, Manager giving approval for transfer of living pathogenic organisms.
- Playground, 1935 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Agreement with New York City Park Dept. to use for a public playground land between 67th and 68th Sts. and First Ave. and York Ave.
- Princeton Department of Animal Pathology, 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Purchase, leases, agreements for assorted parcels of land and houses.
- Princeton Department buildings, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Building costs, agreement, specifications.
- Radium, 1920 1933 1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Arrangements and inventory.
- Retirement for employees, 1939 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Record of single premium for back service Corrected June 30, 1939.
- Social Security I.D. number (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Taxation exemption, 1916 1920 1932 1935 1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Assorted correspondence with U.S. Treasury and New York City on tax status of RIMR.
- Tryparsamide, 1923-1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Licensing agreements and supplemental agreements with various drug mafg. firms for the manufacture of Tryparsamide.
- Workmen's Compensation Commission, 1914 1928 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Regarding self-insurance of RIMR.